<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <h3>FHIR Readiness Levels</h3><a name="maturity"> </a>
  <p>
    Case reporting can integrate systems that have different levels of FHIR readiness:
    <dl>
      <dt>FHIR Naive</dt>
      <dd>Existing tool with limited resources or desire to upgrade to include FHIR support.  Have back-end access to database or way to generate tabular reports.  </dd>

      <dt>FHIR Aware</dt>
      <dd>Basic FHIR Questionnaire support available for simple data exports from template reports.  Can initiate FHIR API calls.  Metadata synchronized using IHE profiless (SVCM, mCSD)</dd>

      <dt>FHIR Native</dt>
      <dd>Full FHIR stack, data model and supporting tools are within the system.  Can generate robust FHIR resources and data models and metadata has been synchronized using IHE profiles (SVCM, mCSD)</dd>
    </dl>

    
  </p>


  <h3>Case Report Forms</h3><a name="case_report"></a>  
  <p>
    The specification of a case report form comprises two things:
    <ul>
      <li> The specific data fields expected in the case report are defined through the specification of a <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/questionnaire.html">Questionnaire</a> with a Structured <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/sdc/extraction.html#definition-extract">Definition Based Extract</a> as defined in  the Structured Data Capture Implementation Guide.  The Questionnaire is inteded to ease data collection, particularly from systems with lower FHIR maturity </li>
      
      <li> A profile of the <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/composition.html">Composition</a> which will define where the content (e.g.  demographic, clinical) of a case report form should reside.  This profile also represents the domain of resources onto which a <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/composition.html">QuestionnaireResponse</a> extracts.</li>
    </ul>


    <figure>
      <img src="transformers.png" ></img>
      <figcaption>Case Report Transformation Workflow</figcaption>
    </figure>

  </p>

</div>
